back for another week. Um, this is a
long one in terms of slides. So, I'm not
going to spend a lot of time on any one
slide. Uh, just to make sure that I can
do this hopefully in uh, less than an
hour. So, this is the speed round. So,
you guys can pause here and go look at
the agenda for the week if you would
like. Uh, in terms of disclosures, I
really want you to highlight on this. Um
I appreciate all the subscribers that
are reaching out and are thanking me for
the educational side what they're
learning particularly as we move into
something critical that very few people
understand which is personal AI agents
from the consumer agent side it is a
need for everyone to use them and at the
same time the educational side on the
crypto which is going to become as in my
opinion the people that spend the time
on it now today for the next two months
are going to have a huge advantage from
an investment standpoint over the course
of the next year. It was a big week for
me in terms of putting things up for the
subscribers. This I put up 13 different
things including three. This will be the
third video. Uh for those of you who get
the video, subscribers get it with no
ads. Not that that's a reason that you
should subscribe to it, but um doing all
of this and kind of going through it to
make sure that the education side is
accelerating is because of the crypto
launch, but also because consumer agents
happen at the same time. So there's a
new report up on consumer agents there
because I believe this is as important
as what we went through in November of
last year with Opus 4.5 in the beginning
of the enterprise agents from a token
perspective. Uh bonds and breath the
main story. I did a subscriber video
this week. Uh if you didn't see it you
should go to the site and pull it down.
The slide deck is there. I do that for
all the subscriber videos which means
you can just go through it. I go through
the history of bond yields. Uh this is
being over dramatic. I'm going to go
through the reasons why. I'm not going
to take you on the same journey as I did
in the subscriber one. I'm going to have
some of the same slides, but I want to
make sure you you you go through this.
When you see rates moving up and you
have breath moving down, not only does
that make perfect sense, but it is
insane to me that people are sitting
there saying that this is going to be
like the.com bubble. So, I'm going to
take you through a the reasons why this
is different, b what things in the
market you can look for for what will
warn you. Having lived and traded
through this when I was already an
experienced person, I was running the
S&P options book for Morgan Stanley
during the do-com bubble, writing an S&P
side on it. I've been through all of
this. This is not the same thing. First
of all, for everyone who's too young and
for everyone who's too stubborn, uh,
from the great financial crisis, Lehman
Brothers right here, to basically the
normalization of Fed rates after COVID,
here's what happened. We had basically a
lost 14-year period where we had
negative yielding bonds. Negative
yielding bonds, something that is not
possible. We had negative yielding
bonds. So, this period should not count
when you're looking at a chart. What is
happening now? If it was this, no one
would care. But because we're doing this
with this, everyone freaks out, which is
just insane to me. So they start writing
things like, "This is going to take down
the world. You've never seen this
before. We have too much debt." As of
right now, we are not even in the
midpoint of a normal range for when
nominal GDP is where it is today.
Nominal GDP is about 6.5%.
We should be probably closer to seven. I
will start worrying about bonds at least
from being a long-term problem if we
start getting above seven in a major
way. It does matter as it goes higher.
Certain parts of the market starts to
underperform, but those parts of the
market have been underperforming for
years as I'm going to highlight. This is
why it's a different economy. So, I'm
not going to go through every single
thing here, but I do want you to pay
attention to this part if no other.
pause and go through every single thing
or go watch the subscriber video. The
technology sector including Alphabet,
Microsoft, Google, Amazon, Nvidia, Meta
and Tesla which are in different sectors
and not in the technology. They were
just barely above 10% and the great
financial crisis as a waiting.
They're now 56%.
This is the main reason why rates don't
matter compared to back then. So again,
these companies did not take debt during
that period. These companies are not
based on it. Yes, they're taking debt
now, but it doesn't matter as I go
through this why it doesn't matter. Uh
the main point is the economy has
changed dramatically since then purely
from that basis. And if you don't
believe me, in 2015, so not at the great
financial crisis for GM and the four
main the four major homebuilders, they
had revenues of 333 billion in 2015.
They have 432 for a kagger of just 2.4%.
They've been sucking wind for the last
however many years. This is what Nvidian
Micron had in revenues combined those
years, 21 billion. Here's Nvidian Micron
now 535 billion. These names deserve to
go down when rates go higher. They need
rates to go down. It should not be a
surprise. These companies are, it's not
even a comparison how small they are.
Their market cap is is smaller than the
revenue. There's nothing to talk about
in this. It's a joke. When you add in
Google, Meta, Apple, Amazon, Microsoft,
that's another 2.4
trillion, not in market cap, in
revenues.
Here's where they were back then. It was
actually comparable to some degree. This
is a completely different economy.
Anyone that is going before 2015 and
telling you what happened before then
because rates went higher is comparing
it to a time that doesn't exist. If you
don't believe me there, here are the
estimates
for next year's earnings or revenues for
Nvidia. This is where they're going to
finish this year. So 410 to 700, let's
just round it to 300 billion in delta.
That's the increase that is expected and
that is based off what Jensen Yuang
already said. You know the number is
going to be above it. So we're talking
about equal to the entire revenues for
the year for these companies for this
year. That's how much Nvidia is going to
increase next year. So when you're
listening to people tell you this, I'm
telling you this is a fact. strategists
who called for a broadening out this
year are not admitting that they were
wrong and they're hoping that the market
crashes so they can get bailed out. This
is not a guess from me. I've seen this.
I've jumped into X a couple times this
week because I find it insane that
people are not realizing that the market
cap has changed. 78 companies make up
56%
of the market. And these companies are
nonyclical. They are not hurt by rates
moving from 5% to 5.3. There are a lot
of old economy names, not the digital
economy, the old economy names that are
basically getting taken out. If you
don't believe me, financial conditions
is something every macro strategist
talks about. From 1971 to 1999, this is
the fitting of what would happen if
rates went higher. Financial conditions
would tighten. Here's what's happened
since then.
No change. It doesn't matter. This is
from 2010 to 2026.
You want to see it broken out? The 70s
rates went higher. Tightening in the
market. Rates went higher. Financial
conditions. It's not just it's been
going on since the launch of the
computer. So, this is something that's
been happening. If you want to say how
big the number is, sometimes you just
got to put it into perspective. Here is
the combination of year-over-year change
in 10ear yields plus Fed funds looking
back over history. So, this is the
rolling one-year change in basis points.
Does this really look scary? When you're
comparing this to 2022, which I will
repeat, this did not turn into a
recession. That should be a signal that
you shouldn't be worried about rates
here. Look, boom. Did we have Silicon
Valley Bank end up in trouble here? And
everyone likes to jump on, oh, let's add
that to the mix. That wasn't a blip on
anything. It didn't change economics. It
didn't change anything. So, why is
Breath weakening? Well, we had the yield
curve basically flattening, which is the
rates way of saying there's more higher
probability of recession, but really
this is just a representation of rates
moving higher because this was
unfortunately for the market a bare
flattener. So, we had rates going up
across the curve. They were just going
up faster in the short end because we
were building in more expectations of
Fed rate hikes. Well, that changed
dramatically this week because John
Williams came out and basically said no
hike in October. We got a weaker PCE and
then we got weaker payroll data. So,
breath at some point maybe it'll
stabilize. I'm not saying expect Breath
to get much better, but maybe when we
get through earnings and companies start
talking how they're not seeing the
dramatic change, I think that's when
you'll go because this is a one
correlation move amongst it. I'll show
that too. NDX over the S&P.
Everyone who bail, you know, has been
worried about the AI trade. Well, NDX
over S&P is going higher. This is the
relationship to the S&P. Basically,
we've been consolidating now in the S&P
really since June when the AI trade
broke down and now we're rebuilding it.
And at some point here, I would expect
us to go higher. Here's the thing to
watch. So, as I mentioned during my time
during the dotcom bubble, this is what
was going on with staples over the S&P.
So, as you had breath going down, guess
what was going on? People were rotating
away from
the stuff that was risky and they were
moving it into the safe names. So, it
moved in here. But that's not just it.
Staples over the S&P remained incredibly
strong for a long time. We are basically
now going through where tech had a hard
time during this period. This is all
during the doc the the iPhone side. So
staples over the S&P held in and
everyone was wondering how this was
possible. And the reason was because we
had negative yielding debt. And so
instead of buying bonds, you would buy
staples or utilities. Well, now Staples
versus S&P is making new lows.
You don't believe me? Here's the breath
from 20 2008 to 2023. And basically
anytime we had a a breath selloff, which
is the white line, you'd have staples
falling relative or you've had staples
rallying versus the S&P. So this is
inverted. So again, I I I don't know how
to say this uh enough for you guys. Uh
when we get to a point where there's
something to worry about with breath,
you're going to see people rotating into
defensives. I've shown this before. I
showed this on a subscriber video.
financials relative to utilities. So
banks have been very weak. I'm going to
go through the banks because they're
going to have a bank apocalypse uh just
like SAS did and I think we're in the
early stages of something that'll be
probably a Q1 story. Um financials
relative to utilities when this is going
higher this means growth is good because
banks which are interest rate sensitive
and certainly get hurt with credit
problems. People rotate into utilities.
So this is a rate situation. Now, equal
weight tech. We keep hearing how equal
weight's getting destroyed. No, it's
not. Equal weight tech made a new
all-time high today. Uh, equal weight
tech relative to equal weight S&P, which
has been going down. Again, these things
are correlated. So, eventually we'll go
higher. Tom Mlen basically going through
the new highs, new lows. This is
typically a bottoming sign for the
market. So, is that the way we should
look at it? Well, I think so because
look who is making all the new lows. So,
this is from the compound and friends.
Uh, big shout out to them because I
thought this was a great way of breaking
it down and I listen to those guys a
lot. Um, chartkidmatt.com.
You can go get his charts on there. But
basically showing that staples seeing a
spike in new lows, utilities having a
massive spike in new lows. Tech no spike
in new lows. Financials news that's a
good growth sign. Um that's how oversold
we were. So if you take a 14-day RSI of
breath going back to 1999, actually we
have data back to 2004. This blue line
here is 25. So, I wanted to go back and
look and see, well, how do these things
do when we hit those levels? Okay. Well,
here's all the times that the RSI the
day it hit or broke below 25. So, this
date, you guys can go back and go look
the date that we broke it. Here are the
hit rates going forward. These are the
returns going forward. Again, I think
when you look at this stuff and you see
that breath is usually a bottoming sign,
uh, rather than something negative, and
in particular, if you just go look kind
of at the course of the last whatever
years, aside from the great financial
crisis, you're heavily skewed on the
six-month performance to the upside. Uh,
this is the reason why strategists are
bearish. when you make an outlook call
at the beginning of the year and you
call for a broadening out trade. I've
watched a lot of ex people be bragging
because they were long Europe short the
US. All of these different things. Well,
that's completely unwind now because
rates and oil have gone higher and the
weak have been basically
underperforming. But also the AI trade
continues to defy the doubters. This red
line here is chat GPT. This is equal
weight S&P relative to S&P. You are
talking to someone who believes that all
equities are vulnerable over the course
of the next 5 years. But first, we have
to get rid of all of the small
businesses that don't supply the
infrastructure for AI. Yes, I will
repeat it. We need to get rid of all the
businesses. They are being replaced by
AI native businesses, which is I why I
reach out to you to sign up for my
service to at a minimum get your kids to
be using AI. I think I've had a good hit
ratio now with college kids and my son
in particular with using the tools that
I'm showing and how to think about it
because most of the video I put together
is done with AI. So here is equal weight
versus capweight S&P correlated to the
ISM. So when we got this move higher, we
were supposed to get a bounce which we
did. Now if rates had stayed low, I
think this trade would have continued
for at least the rest of the year. But
because rates in oil, and this is what
sent it down first was oil. Then we got
the bounce back up, but then we got the
rate problem and the oil problem. It
makes perfect logical sense. But those
names don't matter to the economy.
BKX close below the 200 day moving
average. Um, like I said, I think
there's a bank apocalypse that is
starting just like I talked about a SAS
apocalypse beginning in the third
quarter of last year or the fourth
quarter. By the fourth quarter, I was
talking about the fact that the agents
were here. Well, we have another agent
move which is personal agents which get
into crypto which I'll go through. But
we had our first kind of viral thing
that Torston Sllock sent out this week
basically talking about how agents will
make the logical decision to move money
and take away the fees that are on
yields. That is just one part of the
agentic side. Um I believe and again I'm
putting all of this in there that you
will be living and I believe this is
true and I'll be talking about Joseph
Chalum. I'll give you guys some
homework.
But over the course of the last three
weeks, I've had multiple conversations
with people about Mastercard and Visa,
and they are trying to defend those
companies. I see zero chance that these
companies are going to benefit in the
long run. It's not that they won't
benefit today and maybe for the next two
years. A bank apocalypse is not about
them going out of business, but a bank
apocalypse is about gradually, just like
it was with Agentic Coding. We get
multiple compression. The software names
are still making money. We've had a
bounce in a lot of them. They are not
out of the woods. I do not see them as
being anything but on a perma bare
market invaluation. And I think banks
are now going to go through the same
thing as I highlight here is what has
happened since crypto or since uh we got
the release of Grockbot.
This is the my 46 token index which is
the crypto ecosystem relative to the BKX
going down going down bare market then
all of a sudden we get the bounce
instinct AI launches their beta version
then we get Muse the crypto rails this
is the way I go through things guys I
bring you facts on what's happening when
they started and try to connect them
back two-year rates during that period
have gone straight up normally crypto
gets thought of in liquidity terms. I've
debated everyone in Bitcoin about the
debasement trade and liquidity as being
the story. It certainly started the move
when we got Bessant coming in in in
August, but then we got Worsh moving
higher. So, you've had a change, but
here's the thing that matters. Cryptos
held in there while rates have gone
higher and not a little bit. We brought
in Fed rate hikes, multiple ones. Here's
the way gold reacted. So, gold broke
down. If this was the basement then
Bitcoin would have followed it. The
crypto side would have followed it. The
reason it's not following it is because
we have a different stage. We have the
agents coming.
Clearly Bessant wants rates to go lower
or at least to do something different.
So I think the Zervos higher was
absolutely uh another warning shot about
hey we don't want rates to get higher.
We don't know how we're going to get
them down. We're going to do something.
Then you get John Williams coming out.
There's no need for urgency. Then you
have the buyback in terms of getting the
six billion. You get the reaction day
one and then of course it turns the
other direction. Um here's where we are
for the week with all of that going on.
The S&P continues to have a beautiful
looking breakout chart at some point
consolidating these gains. While the
breath has been horrible. I showed you
the oversold signal. The fact that the
breath has been so weak, rates went up
and now we've had a situation where
we're going to have a pause on this
stuff. So, I think at some point here
we're going to break higher, especially
since the NDX made new all-time highs
today. And that chart looks very similar
to the S&P. It just looks like it broke
out. Equal weight uh tech, same thing.
Here's the frustration for people. I
hear this from many, many macro
podcasts. They want a trend. There's no
trend. This is copper. Obvious trade.
Can't make any money. I already showed
you gold. Can't make money. Everyone who
had the anti- I want to be long crypto
or AI trades. That's the problem, guys.
If you've been fading crypto and saying
I want to be long gold, I don't want to
be long crypto. Sorry, you're losing. If
you said, I want to be long uh
commodities because this is the trade
for both the debasing side, but it's
also the trade for uh the buildout, the
infrastructure side. That's not working.
Nobody wants to be long the AI stuff
because they're scared. Here's the
dollar. Pain, pain, pain, pain. I mean,
basically a year of pain.
And yet, here's the AI trade. Started
here, consolidation, everyone freaks
out. We get situational awareness, and
now we're just going right back to the
same old story. Um, my constant. So,
that was my 100name portfolio. Here is
the 10 name concentrated one. I just
wanted to show you guys like it worked
almost every day, came back, and since
then, it's gone right back up, and it's
now up 106% for the year. State of the
Markets from Andre Horowitz in terms of
AI. Definitely worth the read. I'm only
going to show you some of the slides. If
you're long the tech earnings,
I mean, this is pretty much what I was
showing you guys, but like this is what
you want to be long, not call it a
bubble. You call it a bubble and you go,
I've seen this before with the dot
bubble, you're paying the price. Because
I've been hearing that now for two
years. I can bring up the videos that I
was doing in 24 or 25. Yeah, 24. And
show you guys the bubble talk. Here's
what you're investing in if you're
playing for anything but that. This is
the reason Breath is so bad is because
the earnings are just not there for home
builders and autos and staples which are
getting disrupted by AI especially as
people are going to live longer. They
have OMIC. Every single trade is a
disruption trade. The alpha is on
shorting the 440, not being
ignoring the fact that they're going
down and thinking it's going to take the
entire economy down. um reports of
obsolescence on chips. So, every time
you hear someone talk about GPUs, and
this is all through uh I guess two weeks
ago, every single chip from Nvidia
continues. There's supposed to be in
decline, guys. When it once it comes
out, it's like a car. It's supposed to
depreciate because there's a better one
the next day. This is what they talked
about in terms of the opportunities
coming up. The reason I want to show
this, more tokens, more tokens, more
tokens, more tokens. Every one of these
means a lot more tokens.
And then we get Micron this week.
Everyone wants to fade Micron. the
amount of crap I got when I said I
bought started buying it back in the
800s from people and I said I wanted to
be involved because I thought it would
go higher over the course of the next
year and I was prepared to build a
sizable position if we went back towards
500. Uh but we never did. We just sat
there. It's not a huge position for me.
It's not as big as Marll or Nvidia, but
I'm still in it and it's not as big as
crypto. But I mean the revenue jumps
11fold as you go through.
We do not see line of sight when supply
catches up with demand because the
demand trends of larger models, growing
context, more concurrency, greater
agents across enterprise and consumer
only continue to drive greater need for
memory.
AI is moving to the edge.
Physical embodied AI. They're seeing
their first deployment of physical AI
and autonomous vehicles. Why does it
consume so much memory? The magnitude of
the increase, the human. These are all
quotes from the earnings call. You're
crazy if you don't believe that the
compute needs are growing. Another part
of the 100 thematic infrastructure
portfolio is a company called Rogers in
the chemical side. I think it's a really
important one. They had an investor day.
So, it wasn't earnings, it was an
investor day, and they took their
numbers up. This was a step up function,
a massive move. Um, basically from $3 to
14. So when you go through this, and I'm
not going to read all of these because
again, this is a long thing I've got
here. We're getting into Reuben time
where everything is about efficiency and
watts, which is why Marllin,
go look what these names did this week.
Our internal target is higher than that
in terms of what they're talking about
in needs. Here is for you guys the
because it was a step up and I love
stepups. And then I go, well, if they're
stepping up and they're having supply
issues, there's tons of places to go
look. Here you go. For those of you who
are not subscribers, don't say I didn't
give you anything without subscribing.
There's a bunch of names on here that
you guys can go look at. These are the
names that connect back to Rogers on the
work that I've done over the course of
the last two years in my writings. So
all I do for those of you who are
subscribers whenever this happens upload
all of my work that you have saved or
just put it in one folder in anywhere
have co-work go into the folder and only
use that data and go out of the hundred
names take what Rogers did and connect
it back and show me what'll have an
important side. So again the packing
compl the power density the heat density
we're starting to get into the point
where heat matters. Most great
investments begin in discomfort. This is
when we start to segue to the consumer
agents and into crypto. Um,
I basically included this part. So, this
is from Howard Marx. Um, and I wanted to
show this just because last year when I
was writing about inference and talking
about Micron,
the push back I got was again the
discomfort people had. Part of it was
tariffs, but part of it was believing AI
was a bubble. So every time you say AI
is a bubble, you've been wrong and it's
cost you dramatically. So we have a new
inflection point here. So tokens grew
dramatically because of inference,
because of memory, and now we're getting
into consumer agents, which I'm selling
you is more demand because we're now
going to have 8 billion people over the
course of the next five years using
personal. It's going to be on your
phone. Everyone has a phone. They're
going to have it. Muse is free. So when
I use Muse, the amount of tokens I'm
using between Grock and Muse is far
bigger than any month I've ever used. So
if you're not using them, great. But I'm
already causing demand issues. This is a
paper I wrote in May 15th of 2025. The
inference inflection, where real time AI
meets real time opportunity. I want you
to read this. While everyone was busy
debating tariffs, AI inference quietly
had its breakout moment. While markets
fixated on trade headlines and the daily
churn of social media noise, think rates
and breath, a far more important macro
trend was again meaning momentum. You
missed AI because of this. Then in June,
the firework shows over. One of the
hardest things for investors to
recognize during an exponential
technological transition is the
difference between new information and
delayed understanding. The Agentic AI
buildout has just begun. And the reason
I want to show this, since that period,
there's been no money to make in AI.
Now, I'm not saying Micron's not going
to continue to make you money, but you
had to go through a 700 point fall, 50%
fall in the stock, and I think it might
go up from the peak another whatever it
was, it was a,000 back then. So, I when
I wrote this paper, Micron was $98. When
I wrote this paper, it was over 1,000.
You don't get windows to wait. So now
I'm going to take you through the
educational side. I have a lot of
podcasts in here. For those of you who
want to get smarter on the situation, go
listen to them. Don't just take what my
summary is in this video. Go listen.
This young kid here is the founder of uh
Instinct AI.
The personal ra the founder argues we
are entering the largest software race
in history. Agents replace interfaces.
Trust becomes everything. I'm going to
emphasize trust again and again. This is
the argument that people give for
Mastercard and Visa. They are wrong,
wrong, wrong. You want trust, you go to
crypto, you go to cryptography, you go
to instant settlement. I will show you
why. You are wrong if you believe trust
in the system is there. It takes time.
And this kid explains trust, not
intelligence, is presented as the
biggest bottleneck. And that's because
of stubborn thinkers. users gradually
provide more permissions as confidence
builds, which means as they use it, they
get less worried about the other issues.
This will happen with crypto as well. It
will take time. Everything takes time.
But when you say this is the way people
trust, I will show you times where I've
heard this before and it came to bite
people big time. Attention economy
versus the agent economy. This is
important for people who think that Meta
and these other places are going to win.
I think this is going to be a feeding
frenzy. The Mag 7 used to have their own
lanes. Now they're going to be fighting
with each other over the same TAM. I
think it is very very difficult because
it's going to depend on what you're
comfortable with and where you spend
your attention. And that's why the
attention economy which is where we've
had the Mag 7 in different verticals now
we're going to have it harder and the
agent economy is very very different and
businesses must adapt. He talks about
that product design is becoming
psychology and that's what I mean. It's
becoming something that is very very
challenging uh to deal with. I'm moving
away from being with my phone because
Muse is sending me things during the day
multiple multiple times. I can't even
tell you how many things I get on Muse
all day long. The compute problem. This
is one of the most interesting parts.
Exponential compute demand. User growth
compounds daily while proactive agents
require constant background reasoning.
Meaning compute demand scales much
faster than traditional applications.
The founder explains why buying GPUs
becomes extraordinarily difficult.
Infrastructure lead times stretch
months. This is the most important part
in there. He's telling you how difficult
the compute side is.
They already have 1 billion annualized
transaction volume. Think about that.
We're at the point where commerce is
happening. 50% of that volume is travel.
He goes through the daily user growth.
Look at these numbers. 10 10 to 11%.
Again, it's early, but it's fine. 40%
remember that trust thing. Give Instinct
a personal credit card within 3 weeks.
80% retention after connecting sensitive
information. The amount of compute that
you need access to is now doubling
effectively
every week.
So,
it's going to be an order of magnitude
more than what we thought we needed.
They're different than coding agents. It
becomes a new source of compute demand.
I'm not going to read the whole thing
anymore, but basically, no matter how
you take it, guys, if you haven't
increased your memory needs, I want to
bring you back to something that I've
shown you that Goldman Sachs put out.
I've shown it for months. We are in the
first, yes, the first inning of of of
token consumption. So, whatever silly
things you're looking about about
overall spend and all these things and
going through it, you're missing it.
Remember, and I saw this today, I didn't
include it in the video, but the total
revenue this year for OpenAI and
Anthropic combined, which is going to be
about a hundred billion dollars
combined, not the ARR, but their actual
revenue is going to be greater than the
entire
software sector.
So again, when you go through this and
you start thinking this money is coming
from somewhere. So people that thought
that the only TAM that they would get
would be on the software side, the
increase this year is bigger than what
the increase is for the rest of
software. They're taking it from other
places for sure. Meta expands Muse to
small businesses. OpenAI launches dots.
So they've got their first competitor.
Grockbot now connects to your finances,
your bank card, investment accounts, new
finance. Again, thank crypto. Why didn't
Google build Muse? It is kind of amazing
that Google has fallen so far behind in
terms of getting stuff out. Uh this is
just another thing that came out this
week in terms of another product. This
is called FO. Uh just more agents uh
personal AI bots will blow the everyday
tech user away in the next few months.
In the past month, we've noticed the
usefulness of these bots has gone off
the charts. I completely agree. And
that's the thing that I mentioned in
last week's video, uh, which was how
much things changed from the Zuckerberg
town hall to that. So, because this is
an important point and because I wanted
to take it in, I did put on the website
a 25page report. Now, this report is
using all of the research I already did.
It's taking the hundred names that are
in my basket and basically going through
and showing you like I did with Rogers,
but now from the entire thing who
benefits from personal assistance, edge
AI, embodied AI in a step-up function.
So, it's not changing the enterprise
benefits. It's just saying how will this
impact the other names because this will
add to their earnings going forward. So,
I go through the difference between the
two of them. There's a lot of parts in
this and because it's coming out so
fast, I think it's important for you
guys to go spend the time. Smartphones,
AIPCs, wearables, smart home. We are in
the agentic physical AI side because you
have to remember agent swarms mean the
technology is good enough for agents,
which means we're getting closer to
humanoids, to FSD, to all of that. So,
start pushing those. Whatever you
thought the time period was, they're
coming faster. the two names that come
out to give you an idea of the way this
goes. So the direct side, the edge side,
the cloud side, what is
the ranking they get. So again, this is
using um uh a new tool that I went
through. So I'm doing this via the
reports that I did. So the research is
there any new stuff, but then I'm using
Jev tool uh on this. The other thing I
did, so this week there will be two
weekly dashboards up for the hundred
names. So you guys can start finding the
names that you want to be involved in as
the breath continues to increase and
these names are going to many of them
are going to go to all-time highs. Um I
did a weekly one as well. I'm going to
replace the one that I do each week with
one that has weekly data as well. So as
of now you can see for those of you who
use it all of the stuff is the same but
now there's weekly parts as well. I just
want to highlight that because I know a
lot of you have prompt set up and things
like that. You bring it up. I take the
the prompt that's there and explain to
your LLM what's going on. Reach out to
me if you have an issue, but both of
them I'm uploading the weekly and the
regular one. And then based on how
people are doing with the weekly one,
I'll just stay with the one. Um, this is
the prompt that I'm bringing out. So, I
put together an analyst prompt for this
to basically help people that have just
come on because a lot of crypto people
have come on. You need to be on top of
the AI side because they're connected.
The reason I want crypto people to learn
AI, it's going to make you smarter and
feel more confident in crypto being in a
bull market. Most crypto people have
been involved have seen this before
where they get a head fake and it goes
right back to lows. I've heard this
repeatedly. And for people who have a
lot of money already in crypto that
don't want to get involved, I understand
if you already have money there, but
start paying attention to not only the
list of the names, but also the
technical side of AI. It will match up
and they're moving. Here's the breath
number, the most recent one. So, the
20-day, we've jumped up to 74.
You can see it's the highest number
since the peak. The 50-day is up at 69.
Again, the highest number since the
peak. You've now got a turn up, a
decisive turn up in the above the 200
day moving average. And the 50-day slope
just jumped by seven points. So, we have
now a good scenario. and the average to
range V has continued to collapse. So we
are 20% that's the average from the 52-
week high. We still have 20% of room.
This number to me is going to continue
to fall like I've been talking about. Go
through the list if you haven't used Jev
yet. Absolutely use it. Absolutely load
it up. Has been a magical thing for me.
I'm not going to show you the output and
what it is, but basically what I'm using
Jev for is exactly it does a scoring
system. It goes through everything. It
is a It puts into the entire context
into play. So, if you haven't spent time
looking at it, I highly recommend
figuring out how to get it connected to
either Claude or Astra. You can do it.
It's through an MCP. If you haven't done
it yet, I highly recommend this is the
analysis that it goes. So, use the Jev
portfolio tool again and make sure this
is incorporated into the analysis. So,
this is with the Aentic consumer
inflection report going through and
giving me probabilities. the agentic
regime strengthening 100% probability
based on everything that it's seeing in
terms of the data. So, and the biggest
change it said was Qualcomm. So, that
report uses Jev in there. For those of
you have not had your kids on this video
and have not subscribed and then got
your kids subscribed, this is my son
texting me this week when I asked when
we started talking. We check in about
what he's doing in AI and I was asking
him how his internship or his co-op is
doing. Um, I have literally enjoyed
working here so much. I'm telling you,
as someone who lives in Williamsburg
with a bunch of people around the age of
my son, so my son is 21, uh, he would be
a junior in college, but he's doing this
internship. The amount of people in
their 20s who say I have literally
enjoyed working here so much is close to
zero. It is literally adapt or die,
though. Whenever I have meetings and
they are walking through a process, I'm
always like, why on earth is this not
already automated? That's why he's
having a great time because he knows how
to use AI. This is amazing. And the most
proud moment I was is when I asked him,
"Have you used Jev Tool yet?" He said,
"Yeah." I said, "How could you have used
it so far? It only came out a month
ago." And he said, "I stay on the X all
day long looking for the newest features
that I can upload." Because he's already
AI native. College has become less
needed for him. He could already work
and be doing phenomenal because he's
able to do things that 99.9% of the
people on the planet can't do. He's a
finance major. He only had a Python boot
camp which was like a oneweek thing that
I gave him. Get your kids going. Have
them watch this. It will inspire them.
Trust me, I have a lot of them reaching
out to me. Um,
I want to bring up this guy. I spoke to
Ilia
uh Pulukin
uh this week. amazing story. He was one
of the Transformer 8, which is one of
the eight co-authors on the Transformer
paper that Google put out that allowed
for Gen AI the way we see it today. So,
I spoke to him because he's with this
protocol near he's the founder. Um, very
interesting story. I talked a good deal
about it with Pomp. Uh,
very impressed with the kid. He's a
young guy, but obviously very smart.
He's not as young as he was in the
Transformer side, but NEAR is one of the
tokens that I've mentioned. Uh, one of
the ones I've invested in personally,
but this episode with no priors is
really what I wanted to mention as a
segue here. This is important for you if
you're a mutual fund, if you're a hedge
fund, any asset manager. If you go
listen to this episode, the reason it's
important is because this was in 2023. I
think it was May of 2023. No priors is a
very good uh technology
podcast and they talked to him. So
here's someone who
this is in the peak of now people being
hired. I mean this guy worked on the
transformer paper. He obviously could go
to any one of the labs and yet he was
working on Near and his story on what it
is is amazing. So Near was set up and
this is again 2023 this interview
believing that the blockchain was an
operating system for AI agents. He talks
about all of this agentic side back in
2023. Again, ChachiBT had just been
launched 6 months earlier. to listen to
visionaries who have an AI background
talk about how the blockchain is
necessary and why he personally decided
this was the best path for him to go to
where he had left Google to do a coding
agent company like open ai openai and
anthropic you have to go listen to it if
you're curious and want to learn Ily is
the guy to go listen to from that this
is the way it is if AI agents are
equipped with a blockchain account they
will become an economic agent that is
able to pay other people as other people
AIs do. He talked about this whole thing
and it was his reason with his AI
company that he decided this was a thing
because he couldn't make payments to
people around the world and the tested
the blockchain and it wasn't ready. So
he decided to go out and build an L1
basically the infrastructure the
internet necessary for the payment side
to be ready for AI agents. It's a great
story. It's worth listening to. He did a
more recent one which was uh two weeks.
Oh no, this was uh almost last week. I
listened to him again and again again. I
spoke to him this week uh on a call
because I had spoken about them and it's
very weird that the founders of
companies will sit on the phone with
you. That doesn't happen in public
companies. But in private companies
where they are just growing, this is the
Peter Lynch thing. You get to talk to
these people and find them before
everyone else does. this John Gillan
article uh interview with Tom Lee I'm
going to reference again as I move
forward
the William Mugayar
uh this is a podcast so I'm going to
give you guys the subscribers all of
these podcasts that I'm referencing the
weekly podcast info will go out Sunday
at 9:00 a.m. Look for it. This is the
one to really go through. Almost all of
them are related to crypto. But this is
where your education begins. William is
a brilliant guy. He was involved in
Napster in the '9s. Then he got involved
in Ethereum. He and I had a conversation
as well this week. He has a new book
coming out. He and I spoke because he
also heard me talk about it. These
founders and these highly, highly smart,
experienced people want to talk. And the
reason they want to talk is they can
feel where we are because they've been
building things for this moment. It
wasn't for 2021. It wasn't for 2017. It
was for now. So, in this uh in those two
interviews, the reason I want to bring
them up is it talks about Ethereum, how
it's mispriced, how it should be thought
of as four connected pieces. Now, this
is Mugayar's uh side. I'm going to get
into Tom Lee's side and another person,
Joseph Chalum, who worked at Black
Rockck as well, but Ethereum is
something you need to understand.
Ethereum is effectively the internet in
my opinion. uh and how you value the
internet right now is all of the apps on
top of it. That is not the way crypto is
going to work, but there will be some
connection to it. So, Ethereum is
important for everyone to go through and
I think William does the best point
because he's been involved in the space
from the beginning, but he also was
involved in peer-to-peer with Napster.
He gets it. He was also at Ula Packard a
long time ago. So, this is an
experienced person, very, very bright
and he both Ilia and him said a lot of
things. dot con dots that connected for
me. I don't get that too many points
when I talked to people. So between the
two of them, one hour I probably had
seven things that I left with. Um this
is just a summary of William. You guys
can look at this on your own in terms of
the way to value it. Joseph Chalum um he
is now the CEO of Sharplink. He was at
BlackRock.
He's probably the closest person uh to
Tradfi in terms of the finance side.
He's the person you want to listen to
for the agentic big bang. So, this is a
podcast that came out this week
and this is the bank apocalypse. We
estimate agents will touch about 4,000
trillion dollars of fees over the next
decade for the financial industry.
Ethereum is financial in in uh
infrastructure trust commodity for the
future financial rails. It'll be the
settlement layer for almost all of
finance. Why agents change finance?
Traditional rails can't handle agents.
Everything that he talks about in here
is all about agents being the catalyst.
Again, I'm not just throwing this at you
and going through it. I'm giving you the
people so you don't have to believe it
from me. This is the research I do. This
is the education you get. Ethereum is
effectively the toll road to
tokenization. And that's Larry Fin's
framing. Um, again, another one that you
guys will get on this. So, here are the
three of them. Ether will end up being
the trust commodity for the future
financial rails. Ethereum security layer
and finan finality and trust. The
paradigm shift is about trust. You guys
notice trust, trust, trust. I showed you
Noah trust. Noah from Instinct AI. You
have to understand that when you say the
current system you can trust, you cannot
trust it. You cannot. And I will explain
why. So if you're older and you have
money, you have something to lose. for
younger people and for AI native
businesses who depend on instant
settlement and don't want their money
hung up somewhere throughout the system.
There's a corn
car horn in the background. Sorry, you
guys have to listen to this. Um, are we
going to trust them if they're running
Visa Rails and JP Morgan accounts to
make sure that they're not going to
drain our financial resources? I feel
like every week now there's something
that goes on. Last week it was my uh it
was my uh uh Siri talking on here. So,
sorry about the horn in the background.
uh level of trust within financial
systems. All right, let me go close the
window and see if that'll help.
Didn't need to do it. See, you guys get
a show with Jordy. It's not just It's
real time. It's one It's a It's a If you
thought there was a script, there's no
script. There's no editing. Um AI agents
weaken the old human trust model. Need
We need machine verile verifiable trust.
Lee,
AI creates a new trust problem.
Absolutely. The old architecture of
trust is breaking. Absolutely. ETH
becomes the trust commodity for the new
financial rails. This is the title of
William Muggayar's book. I'm doing a uh
a sentence in it in terms of the
forward. Uh
I believe in what he's going and this
trust shift thing is brilliant. This is
the part where like it was with other
things which I'm going to highlight now.
Remember where you were with iPhone vers
Blackberry, wherever you were working,
whether you didn't trust the iPhone or
didn't want to use the iPhone, whether
your corporation wouldn't let you go on
the iPhone for security, and now the
iPhone is thought of as the most secure
place.
This was a huge deal. So the Blackberry
to me is Visa, Mastercard. You can sit
there and pretend this stuff is things
you don't understand. Go back to Howard
Marx. Just because this brings
discomfort for you doesn't make it the
best investment. This needs to prove to
be a winner. I find 0.0 chance that Visa
and Mastercard will be the winners. Will
they participate? Yes, just like
Salesforce.com.
But you have to be a growth business. AI
native businesses and demographics are
not going to use this. They are going to
use cheaper things. So will big
companies and people that have lots of
money continue to use Visa, Mastercard?
maybe for a while. But when you're
investing in growth, you have to realize
that the ecosystem is changing now. And
that is going to be billions of
entrepreneurs like my son, like me
building businesses and revenue streams
that are competing with other places.
And everything to me is about putting it
on the crypto rails if you use agents
because the agents want it. There is
absolutely no doubt. So, I've given you
Ilia. I've given you Tom Lee. I've given
you Joseph Chalum. I've given you now
something you can look at and go, "Yeah,
was I one of those guys that thought
this would be the trusted thing? Did I
work for a company that thought that
it's not real?" And so, I want to give
you part of the reason why and then give
you something that William told me,
which uh again, Muggy are. So, agents
demand speed. And this is the part that
I think people say for Master and Visa
card, it's just not that important. No
one needs that kind of speed, which I
disagree with. Uh, but when you wire
money on a Friday night
and it doesn't get into your bank
account until Monday
and you might think, where's your money?
Well, we have to go through a lot of
different places. So, it's not only
slow. The reason it's slow is because it
needs to go through a bunch of checks
and balances. Here are the hackers.
Every time that it doesn't settle,
there's an issue. So speed is also a
safety feature. If you haven't factored
it into your thinking, you must. And if
you don't know that, here is an example.
GameStop, remember in Jan 21, we had the
freak out. Well, it created a lot of
issues because of margin calls and all
kinds of stuff. So what happened over
the we went from T+1, T+2 to T+1. And
William pointed that out. That was the
trigger point. It was GameStop. It was a
situation where too much volume happened
in too short a period and there were all
kinds of margin issues. I will let you
know it took multiple years, three and a
half years. This is the friction with
inside the current system to make the
change to go to T+1. But the reason it
went to T+1 to was to reduce the risk.
They found the faster the settlement,
the less the risk in that situation.
With agent swarms now, you don't want
your money sitting out in Never
Neverland. we want to immediately
settle. Here we are the latest updated
numbers so far for the month of October
there for those of you who are looking
at it. Um it gets reweed remember. So we
reweed the index or I reweed the index
September 30th. So the names got reweed.
That's the benchmark waiting now for all
of them. And the index level when I show
you the charts and things that keeps
everything constant. And then we just
reweigh it uh just like you would with
an index in stocks. Month to date, been
a quiet day. Got off to a huge start on
Friday on the payroll numbers, then
cuffed in. Here is the breath and trend.
If you're not involved here so far, uh
you're missing out on a bunch of things.
Uh again, here's the crypto rails
relative to the banks. So if you agree
with me that Mastercard Ves and all the
banks are going to have their business
disrupted not just on the payment side
but the tokenization side as well then
you should subscribe and go look at my
crypto video. So I did crypto why now
last week which went through a lot of
the different reasons this week is on
learning the stack making sure you start
to learn the verticals for the next five
weeks. I will give you two of the 10
verticals. Think of them as themes or
sectors. Um, I will give you the charts
on them all and then I will give you
prompts to do the homework along with
the videos. The two I did this week, AI
agents in the machine economy and stable
coins and synthetic dollar systems. Uh,
Peter Lynch is the inspiration for why
I'm doing this stuff. I believe for
everyone, especially younger people, but
anyone who's involved in this
personally, this is the critical time to
be involved in something that the banks
don't cover that has a fundamental bid
to it that is massive. So if you believe
everything I said to now, you have to
know the big money has not invested
there. And it's coming to Ethereum, it's
coming to Salana, it's coming to
Bitcoin, but it will also spread
throughout the ecosystem as people as
the fundamental people like Ilia and
like William, they're getting calls much
more now. I'm hearing this. I'm getting
them more from asset managers. The FOMO
is growing. So I'm not going to read the
whole thing to you, but this is the
reason why thinking of Peter Lynch at
this point is important. Uh, this is the
end result of a prompt that I have. You
can see it's 13. I'm going to, again,
this is going to go up in the subscriber
wall. I'm not going to go through it,
but this is meant to help you with these
crypto names to where you can just pick
one of the names of the 46, add this
prompt in, run it, and it will give you
a ton of detail on the name. The best
place to learn about these things is on
the internet. The banks, when they get
involved in this, I don't know how
they're going to learn. Maybe they'll
subscribe to my video. Maybe they'll go
get get on there, but they're going to
have to hire. How many analysts do you
have to hire to actually know what these
tokens do? This is a huge advantage to
use AI. So, here's the prompt. It's
called the Peter Lynch Framework Invisor
Labs vertical analysis prompt. You can
read through what it's going to do, but
this will help you learn about them.
Take the 46 names, break them into these
10 sectors so you can think just like
you do in the market. I'm giving you one
index for everyone who's saying to me
they want 10 names or five names or
this. No chance. Crypto is a riskier
place. The reason ETFs are great is
because it's got 46 names. The reason
I'm equal weighting it and not cap
weighting it is because to benefit from
this, I think the equal weight is good.
Think about what I just said. I don't
think equal weight is good for the stock
market because I believe we're losing
thousands of companies including the
public companies being disrupted like
banks and software companies. But on
this side, the money is going to flow
from that space into this space because
it's flowing into the AI native
businesses which will use this. That's
the way you have to think about it. When
tokenization comes, we will go from the
mag seven of growth to the mag billion
of growth. We will lose many, many
companies that will never grow again
like Ford, like GM. That should have
been gone a long time ago, but we've
prevented that from happening. So again,
13 things. you will be smarter at the
end of this week. I guarantee you if you
subscribe, I work very hard to provide
you that and to use AI to help me give
you at least something to be good to
look at. So, he's been busy. He's a good
guy. If you guys haven't reached out to
him, Mark will help you out. Just reach
out to him this week. A bare market
within a bull market. I put this out
this week. And again, if you didn't get
a chance to read it, own scarcity. how
AI and tokenization
could reshape valuation for all
companies. Joseph Chalum put this out
this week. Highly recommend it.
If you don't believe me, follow
Wall Street.
SEC's 5-year transition period. Will
tokenized stocks disrupt Wall Street?
Here are the timelines of all the things
that happened since the Clarity Act
failed to pass.
[sighs] New rules
for the custody of crypto assets. Very
important for investment advisors. This
is from the Federal Reserve Bank of San
Francisco talking about the importance
of stable coins. If you guys don't know
what stable coins are, and I'm showing
you that the government is telling you,
the Fed is telling you, start learning
now. Start understanding stable coins
won't go mainstream on speed alone. Visa
found US adoption intent for
international travelers jumped from 36
to 56 when bank level protection was
added. Why trust is the next
battleground again? Trust, trust, trust.
Swift,
you remember Swift platform transfers,
crossber payments across the existing
rails and digital value. Robin Hood's
next big bet at the Hood Summit, AI bots
that trade while you sleep. I will be
spending more time on this. I am hopeful
that someone on the asset management
side who wants me to do an ETF and
realizes I will not do an ETF. But what
I will do, having run
exchange traded fund business at Morgan
Stanley, knowing program trading and
being a derivative person, knowing how
to execute in a basket, the Agentic side
is the perfect way of my research being
matched up with the names that I have.
So whether it's a crypto place, whether
it's a bank, whether it's Robin Hood,
Mumu, Interactive Brokers, get your act
straight, call up. I'm happy to go
through this. I want my subscribers to
be able to invest in the index and the
names, but I want them also to be able
to use Agentic Trading, Goldman Sachs
going online. These are all this week,
guys. Morgan Stanley builds crypto lab
to test future of Wall Street. They're
setting up a digital asset lab to test
technologies including stable coins,
tokenization, and decentralized finance
applications. Does that sound like
something that isn't going to happen, or
is a bank worried that their growth
might be disrupted? Bank Apocalypse.
City expands digital assets footprint
with Coinbase partnership. Bank
Apocalypse. Big move. 1.83 trillion.
Asset manager Franklin Templeton is
turning mo tokenized money market funds
into active crypto collateral with
Bybit.
TD Cowan joining.
Uh my buddy Chris Perkins wrote this and
for everyone who's worried about how
quantum will hurt crypto, I already
showed you that AI agent swarms are
going to hurt your financial system
wires and everything. We will have
hackings. Pay attention to all the
hackings, the ship hacking that happened
in near Texas coast that we found out
today. Everything is under attack.
Quantum won't kill crypto, but it could
accelerate Wall Street's adoption of
blockchain. Brilliant piece by Chris
Perkins. Thank you for your service, my
friend, and thank you for doing good
work on this. That's all I got.
Finishing with the disclosures.
Hopefully that was Yeah, it looks like
it was about an hour. Sorry for the horn
honking, but at least Siri didn't jump
in. Thanks to all the subscribers. If
you haven't subscribed yet on YouTube,
please subscribe. Give it to your kids.
Let everyone watch this. Send it around
the world. Love you guys. See you.